Mobile: +91-8700087888 ruchi.yadav.cse@gmail.com

**Objective:** Looking for a challenging position in a growth-oriented organization where I can use my knowledge and management skills to achieve desired goals.

Consultant, Digilytics Pvt. Ltd.(Jan 2019- till date) Working in product development team to build a platform which facilitates modern day requirements of businesses. Working primarily on Spring Boot applications in a microservices architecture. Few responsibilities are listed below:

- Enabled communication between microservices using Kafka.
- Enabled resource-locking using Redis.
- Developed a platform to deploy ML-models.
- Developed capabilities to execute models from other microservices.
- Developed capabilities that help facilitate electronic management of paperwork
- Developed capabilities to organize different set of documents based on ML models
- Developed performance monitoring modules of ML-models.

Senior Software Engineer, Cybage Software. (Feb 2018 – Jan 2019) Worked with Expedia, as part of Fraud Detection platform which aims to find fraudulent transactions while booking inventory for customers. The platform has multiple microservices. Working closely with few of the core services. Few responsibilities are listed below:

- Exposing REST apis for new capabilities in Spring framework.
- Creating CI/CD pipelines
- Implementing Role Mapping in Elastic Search cluster
- Performance testing in Elastic Search
- Curator Implementation for automatic creation and deletion of indices.
- Creating queues and exchanges in RabbitMQ for new capabilities.
- Production On-Call support for owned services and debugging production issues.

## **Previous Experience:**

Senior Software Engineer, Oxyent Medical Pvt. Ltd. (August 2016-December 2017 & June 2013 – Feb 2014)

## **Project details:**

**Devices to capture data from monitors & ventilators**. Worked on a project to capture data from machines in an ICU, send that data on cloud & an application on backend to handle the data and perform analytics.

- Software: Fetch data from devices using a Java program, send the data on a Spring Boot application running on cloud and store this data on cloud in Cassandra & Postgres.
- Hardware: Testing PCB, assembling electronic components on the PCB, installing programs on the box.

## **Areas of Expertise**

Programming Languages: Java 8, Spring Boot
 Databases: MySQL, SQLServer, Elastic Search

Cloud: Azure & AWSCRM: SuiteCRM

• **Platforms**: Windows, Linux, OSx.

• **Application Servers:** Apache Tomcat.

• Methodologies: Agile, waterfall.

• Message Brokers: Kafka & RabbitMQ

• Cache: Redis

• **IoT**: Familiarity with Beaglebone Black, NodeMCU, Arduino Mega and programming in embedded C.

## **Educational Qualifications:**

S. No.	Course	Year of	University	G.P.A
1	M.Tech.(Computer Science & Engineering)	passing 2012	Amity University, Haryana	9.88/10.0
2	B.S(Computer Engineering)		Purdue University, USA	3.28/4.0

**References**: Available on request.